<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.0537"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.0537"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.0537/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.0537/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.0537/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.0537/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_205">
        <num>Chapter 205</num>
        <heading>Local Business Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_205_0537">
          <num>205.0537</num>
          <heading>Vending and amusement machines.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The business premises where a coin-operated or token-operated vending machine that dispenses products, merchandise, or services or where an amusement or game machine is operated must assure that any required municipal or county business tax receipt for the machine is secured. The term “vending machine” does not include coin-operated telephone sets owned by persons who are in the business of providing local exchange telephone service and who pay the business tax under the category designated for telephone companies in the municipality or county or a pay telephone service provider certified pursuant to s.364.3375. The business tax for vending and amusement machines must be assessed based on the highest number of machines located on the business premises on any single day during the previous receipted year or, in the case of new businesses, be based on an estimate for the current year. Replacement of one vending machine with another machine during a receipted year does not affect the tax assessment for that year, unless the replacement machine belongs to a business tax classification that requires a higher tax rate. For the first year in which a municipality or county assesses a business tax on vending machines, each business owning machines located in the municipality or county must notify the municipality or county, upon request, of the location of such machines. Each business owning machines must provide notice of the provisions of this section to each affected business premises where the machines are located. The business premises must secure the receipt if it is not otherwise secured.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
