<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/207.0281"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/207.0281"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/207.0281/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/207.0281/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/207.0281/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/207.0281/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_207">
        <num>Chapter 207</num>
        <heading>Tax on Operation of Commercial Motor Vehicles</heading>
        <section eId="sec_207_0281">
          <num>207.0281</num>
          <heading>Registration; cooperative reciprocal agreements between states.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may enter into a cooperative reciprocal agreement, including, but not limited to, the international fuel-tax agreement, with another state or group of states for the administration of the tax imposed by this chapter. An agreement arrangement, declaration, or amendment is not effective until stated in writing and filed with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may enter into a cooperative reciprocal agreement, including, but not limited to, the international fuel-tax agreement, with another state or group of states for the administration of the tax imposed by this chapter. An agreement arrangement, declaration, or amendment is not effective until stated in writing and filed with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agreement may provide for determining the base state for users, users’ records requirements, audit procedures, exchange of information, persons eligible for tax licensing, defining qualified motor vehicles, determining if bonding is required, specifying reporting requirements and periods including defining uniform penalty and interest rates for late reporting, and determining methods for collecting and forwarding of motor fuel taxes and penalties to another jurisdiction and may include other provisions as will facilitate the administration of the agreement.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department may, as required by the terms of the agreement, forward to the proper officers of another state any information in the department’s possession relative to the manufacture, receipt, sale, use, transportation, or shipment of motor fuels by any person. The department may disclose to the proper officers of another state the location of offices, motor vehicles, and other real and personal property of users of motor fuels.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agreement may provide for each state to audit the records of persons based in the state to determine if the motor fuel taxes due each state are properly reported and paid. Each state shall forward the findings of the audits performed on persons based in the state to each state in which the person has taxable use of motor fuels. For persons who are not based in this state and who have taxable use of motor fuel in this state, the department shall serve the audit findings received from another state in the form of an assessment on the person as though an audit was conducted by the department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any agreement entered into under this section does not preclude the department from auditing the records of any person covered by the provisions of this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section and the contents of any reciprocal agreement entered into under this section supersede all other fuel-tax requirements of this chapter for commercial motor vehicles.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="207_0281__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The legal remedies for any person served with an order or assessment under this section are as prescribed in this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
