<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/198.44"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/198.44"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/198.44/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/198.44/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/198.44/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/198.44/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_198">
        <num>Chapter 198</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_198_44">
          <num>198.44</num>
          <heading>Certain exemptions from inheritance and estate taxes.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The tax imposed under the inheritance and estate tax laws of this state in respect to personal property (except tangible property having an actual situs in this state) shall not be payable:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="198_44__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the transferor at the time of death was a resident of a state or territory of the United States, or the District of Columbia, which at the time of death did not impose a death tax of any character in respect to property of residents of this state (except tangible personal property having an actual situs in such state, territory, or district); or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="198_44__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the laws of the state, territory, or district of the residence of the transferor at the time of death contained a reciprocal exemption provision under which nonresidents were exempted from said death taxes of every character in respect to personal property (except tangible personal property having an actual situs therein), and provided that the state, territory, or district of the residence of such nonresident decedent allowed a similar exemption to residents of the state, territory, or district of residence of such decedent.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
