<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.066"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.066"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.066/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.066/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.066/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/205.066/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_205">
        <num>Chapter 205</num>
        <heading>Local Business Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_205_066">
          <num>205.066</num>
          <heading>Exemptions; employees.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An individual who engages in or manages a business, profession, or occupation as an employee of another person is not required to apply for an exemption from a local business tax, pay a local business tax, or obtain a local business tax receipt. An individual acting in the capacity of an independent contractor is not an employee.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="205_066__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An individual who engages in or manages a business, profession, or occupation as an employee of another person is not required to apply for an exemption from a local business tax, pay a local business tax, or obtain a local business tax receipt. An individual acting in the capacity of an independent contractor is not an employee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="205_066__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An employee may not be held liable by any local governing authority for the failure of a principal or employer to apply for an exemption from a local business tax, pay a local business tax, or obtain a local business tax receipt. An individual exempt under this section may not be required by any local governing authority to apply for an exemption from a local business tax, otherwise prove his or her exempt status, or pay any tax or fee related to a local business tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="205_066__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A principal or employer who is required to obtain a local business tax receipt may not be required by a local governing authority to provide personal or contact information for individuals exempt under this section in order to obtain a local business tax receipt.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="205_066__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The exemption provided in this section does not apply to a business tax imposed on individual employees by a municipality or county pursuant to a resolution or ordinance adopted before October 13, 2010. Municipalities or counties that, before October 13, 2010, had a classification system that was in compliance with the requirements of this chapter and that actually resulted in individual employees paying a business tax may continue to impose such a tax in that manner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
