<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/213.018"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/213.018"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/213.018/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/213.018/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/213.018/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/213.018/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_213">
        <num>Chapter 213</num>
        <heading>State Revenue Laws: General Provisions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_213_018">
          <num>213.018</num>
          <heading>Taxpayer problem resolution program; taxpayer assistance orders.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A taxpayer problem resolution program shall be available to taxpayers to facilitate the prompt review and resolution of taxpayer complaints and problems which have not been addressed or remedied through normal administrative proceedings or operational procedures and to assure that taxpayer rights are safeguarded and protected during tax determination and collection processes.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="213_018__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Chief Inspector General shall appoint a taxpayers’ rights advocate, and the executive director of the Department of Revenue shall designate adequate staff to administer the taxpayer problem resolution program.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="213_018__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The taxpayers’ rights advocate may, with or without a formal written request from the taxpayer, issue a taxpayer assistance order that suspends or stays actions or proposed actions by the department when a taxpayer suffers or is about to suffer a significant hardship as a result of a tax determination, collection, or enforcement process.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="213_018__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Relief or remedy may be granted by a taxpayer assistance order only as an extraordinary measure. The process shall not be used to contest the merits of a tax liability or as a substitute for informal protest procedures or normal administrative or judicial proceedings for the review of a tax assessment or collection action or denial of refund.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="213_018__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The running of the period of limitations on assessment shall be tolled from the date of a taxpayer’s request for a taxpayer assistance order until either the date the request is denied or the date specified in the taxpayer assistance order, whichever is applicable.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
