<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.0515"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.0515"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.0515/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.0515/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.0515/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.0515/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_212">
        <num>Chapter 212</num>
        <heading>Tax on Sales, Use, and Other Transactions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_212_0515">
          <num>212.0515</num>
          <heading>Sales from vending machines; sales to vending machine operators; special provisions; registration; penalties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this section:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="212_0515__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212_0515__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Vending machine” means a machine, operated by coin, currency, credit card, slug, token, coupon, or similar device, which dispenses food, beverages, or other items of tangible personal property.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212_0515__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Operator” means any person who possesses a vending machine for the purpose of generating sales through that machine and who maintains the inventory in and removes the receipts from that vending machine.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_0515__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the amount of the tax to be paid on food, beverages, or other items of tangible personal property that are sold in vending machines shall be calculated by dividing the gross receipts from such sales for the applicable reporting period by a divisor, determined as provided in this subsection, to compute gross taxable sales, and then subtracting gross taxable sales from gross receipts to arrive at the amount of tax due. For counties that do not impose a discretionary sales surtax, the divisor is equal to the sum of 1.0645 for beverage and food items, or 1.0659 for other items of tangible personal property. For counties with a 0.5 percent sales surtax rate the divisor is equal to the sum of 1.0686 for beverage and food items or 1.0707 for other items of tangible personal property; for counties with a 0.75 percent sales surtax rate the divisor is equal to the sum of 1.0706 for beverage and food items or 1.0727 for other items of tangible personal property; for counties with a 1 percent sales surtax rate the divisor is equal to the sum of 1.0726 for beverage and food items or 1.0749 for other items of tangible personal property; for counties with a 1.5 percent sales surtax rate the divisor is equal to the sum of 1.0767 for beverage and food items or 1.0791 for other items of tangible personal property; and for counties with a 2 percent sales surtax rate the divisor is equal to the sum of 1.0808 for beverage and food items or 1.0833 for other items of tangible personal property. When a county imposes a surtax rate that is not listed in this subsection, the department shall make the applicable divisor available in an electronic format or otherwise. Additional divisors shall bear the same mathematical relationship to the next higher and next lower divisors as the new surtax rate bears to the next higher and next lower surtax rates for which divisors have been established. If an operator cannot account for each type of item sold thr</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_0515__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An operator of a vending machine may not operate or cause to be operated in this state any vending machine until the operator has registered with the department and has obtained a separate registration certificate for each county in which such machines are located. The department shall establish a toll-free number to report any violations of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_0515__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not apply to vending machines owned and operated by churches, synagogues, or nonprofit or charitable organizations exempt pursuant to s.212.08(7)(z).</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_0515__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to any other penalties imposed by this chapter, a person who knowingly and willfully violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s.775.082or s.775.083.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_0515__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department may adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
