<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/197.322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/197.322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/197.322/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/197.322/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/197.322/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/197.322/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_197">
        <num>Chapter 197</num>
        <heading>Tax Collections, Sales, and Liens</heading>
        <section eId="sec_197_322">
          <num>197.322</num>
          <heading>Delivery of ad valorem tax and non-ad valorem assessment rolls; notice of taxes; publication and mail.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The property appraiser shall deliver to the tax collector the certified assessment roll along with his or her warrant and recapitulation sheet.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="197_322__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The property appraiser shall deliver to the tax collector the certified assessment roll along with his or her warrant and recapitulation sheet.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="197_322__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tax collector shall on November 1, or as soon as the assessment roll is open for collection, publish a notice in a local newspaper that the tax roll is open for collection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="197_322__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within 20 working days after receipt of the certified ad valorem tax roll and the non-ad valorem assessment rolls, the tax collector shall send to each taxpayer appearing on such rolls, whose address is known to him or her, a tax notice stating the amount of current taxes due, discounts allowed for early payment, and that delinquent taxes are outstanding, if applicable. Pursuant to s.197.3632, the form of the notice of non-ad valorem assessments and notice of ad valorem taxes shall be in the form specified in s.197.3635, notwithstanding s.195.022. The tax collector may send such notice electronically or by postal mail. Electronic transmission may be used only with the express consent of the property owner. Electronic transmission of tax notices may be sent earlier but may not be sent later than the postal mailing of the notices. If the notice of taxes is sent electronically and is returned as undeliverable, a second notice must be sent. However, the original electronic transmission used with the consent of the property owner is the official mailing for the purpose of this section. A discount period may not be extended due to a tax bill being returned as undeliverable electronically or by postal mail. The postage for mailing or the cost of electronic transmission shall be paid out of the general fund of each local governing board, upon statement of the amount by the tax collector.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
