<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.855"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.855"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.855/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.855/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.855/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.855/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_215">
        <num>Chapter 215</num>
        <heading>Financial Matters: General Provisions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_215_855">
          <num>215.855</num>
          <heading>Investment manager external communication.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this section, the term:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="215_855__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, the term:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="215_855__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Governmental entity” means a state, regional, county, municipal, special district, or other political subdivision whether executive, judicial, or legislative, including, but not limited to, a department, division, board, bureau, commission, authority, district, or agency thereof, or a public school, Florida College System institution, state university, or associated board.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="215_855__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Investment manager” means a private sector company that offers one or more investment products or services to a governmental entity and that has the discretionary investment authority for direct holdings.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="215_855__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Public funds” means all moneys under the jurisdiction of a governmental entity and includes all manner of pension and retirement funds and all other funds held, as trust funds or otherwise, for any public purpose, subject to investment.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_855__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any contract between a governmental entity and an investment manager must contain the following provisions:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="215_855__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That any written communication made by the investment manager to a company in which such manager invests public funds on behalf of a governmental entity must include the following disclaimer in a conspicuous location if such communication discusses social, political, or ideological interests; subordinates the interests of the company’s shareholders to the interest of another entity; or advocates for the interest of an entity other than the company’s shareholders:</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="215_855__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That the contract may be unilaterally terminated at the option of the governmental entity if the investment manager does not include the disclaimer required in paragraph (a).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_855__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section applies to contracts between a governmental entity and an investment manager executed, amended, or renewed on or after July 1, 2023.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
