<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.61"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.61"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.61/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.61/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.61/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.61/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_215">
        <num>Chapter 215</num>
        <heading>Financial Matters: General Provisions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_215_61">
          <num>215.61</num>
          <heading>State system of public education capital outlay bonds.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The issuance of school bonds, payable primarily from revenues as provided in s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885, as amended, and additionally secured by pledging the full faith and credit of the state, is hereby authorized pursuant to the provisions of s. 9(d), Art. XII of the State Constitution and the provisions of ss.215.57-215.83, “The State Bond Act.”</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="215_61__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The issuance of school bonds, payable primarily from revenues as provided in s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885, as amended, and additionally secured by pledging the full faith and credit of the state, is hereby authorized pursuant to the provisions of s. 9(d), Art. XII of the State Constitution and the provisions of ss.215.57-215.83, “The State Bond Act.”</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_61__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The issuance of bonds to finance or refinance capital outlay projects authorized by the Legislature for the state system of public education, primarily payable from revenues as provided in s. 19, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885, as amended, and additionally secured by pledging the full faith and credit of the state, is hereby authorized pursuant to the provisions of s. 9(a)(2), Art. XII of the State Constitution and the provisions of ss.215.57-215.83, “The State Bond Act.”</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_61__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No bonds authorized by s. 9(a)(2), Art. XII of the State Constitution shall be issued in an amount exceeding 90 percent of the amount which the State Board of Education determines can be serviced by the revenues derived from the gross receipts tax levied and collected pursuant to chapter 203. In determining the amount which can be serviced by the gross receipts tax, the State Board of Education shall use the average annual amount of revenue collected for the tax periods during the 24 months immediately preceding the most recent collection date before the date of issuance of any such bonds, adjusted to reflect revenues that would have been collected had legislation enacted into law before the date of determination been in effect during the 24-month period. Such adjustment shall be based on the assumption that the provisions of the enacted legislation had become effective 24 months before the dates contemplated in the legislation. For purpose of the approval required by s.215.73, official estimates of future collections furnished by the State Board of Education prior to the estimated date of issuance shall be used to determine fiscal sufficiency.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_61__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>With respect to the bonds authorized by s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution, the Division of Bond Finance shall act as the agent of the State Board of Education pursuant to ss.215.57-215.83, “The State Bond Act.”</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_61__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In making the determination as required by subsection (3) of the amount that can be serviced by the gross receipts tax, the State Board of Education shall disregard the effects on the reported gross receipts tax revenues collected during a tax period of any refund paid by the Department of Revenue as a direct result of a refund request made pursuant to the settlement reached inIn re: AT&amp;T Mobility Wireless Data Services Sales Litigation,270 F.R.D. 330, (Aug. 11, 2010). The Department of Revenue shall provide to the State Board of Education, the Division of Bond Finance, and the Office of Economic and Demographic Research the amount of any such refund and the tax period in which the refund is included.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_61__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pursuant to s. 9(a)(2), Art. XII of the State Constitution and s.203.01(1)(c)2., all revenues collected from gross receipts taxes are deposited into the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund. The first priority for the use of the moneys in the trust fund in each fiscal year is the payment of the principal and interest due in such fiscal year on bonds secured by gross receipts tax revenues as provided in s. 9(a)(2), Art. XII of the State Constitution. The State Board of Education shall at least once per month, from gross receipts tax revenues available in the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund, deposit into a separate account within such trust fund one-sixth of the amount due on the next interest payment date and one-twelfth of the amount due on the next principal payment date for all outstanding bonds secured by a pledge of gross receipts taxes. If there are insufficient funds to make the required deposit, the State Board of Education shall deposit an amount equal to the funds available into the separate account and, in the following month, add an amount equal to the previous month’s shortfall to the required deposit. The State Board of Education shall transfer funds deposited into the separate account to the State Board of Administration, as the trustee for bondholders, by the 20th day of the month before a principal or interest payment on bonds issued pursuant to s. 9(a)(2), Art. XII of the State Constitution is due.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
