<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.43"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.43"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.43/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.43/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.43/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/215.43/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_215">
        <num>Chapter 215</num>
        <heading>Financial Matters: General Provisions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_215_43">
          <num>215.43</num>
          <heading>Public bonds, notes, and other securities.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>DEFINITIONS.—As used in this section, the following words and term shall have the following meanings:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="215_43__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>DEFINITIONS.—As used in this section, the following words and term shall have the following meanings:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="215_43__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The word “unit” shall mean any department, board, commission or other agency of Florida, or any county, city, town, village, district or any other political subdivision of the state, heretofore or hereafter created or established, or any board, commission, authority or other public agency or instrumentality which is now or may hereafter be authorized by law to issue bonds.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="215_43__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The term “governing body” shall mean the officer or officers, or the department, board, body, council, commission, authority or other agency which is authorized by law to take the proceedings which are required to authorize or to provide for the issuance of bonds.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="215_43__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The word “bonds” shall include all bonds, notes, certificates and other similar obligations and securities of a unit whether payable in whole or in part from the proceeds of ad valorem taxes, revenues or any other source.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="215_43__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>EXECUTION OF PUBLIC SECURITIES.—</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="215_43__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any bonds heretofore or hereafter authorized to be issued by any unit under the provisions of any general, special or local law heretofore or hereafter enacted and any interest coupons attached thereto may, if so authorized by the governing body of such unit, bear or be executed with the facsimile signature of any official authorized by such law to sign or to execute such bonds or coupons; provided, however, that each such bond shall be manually signed by at least one official of such unit. In case any such law shall provide for the sealing of such bonds with the official or corporate seal of such unit or of its governing body or any official thereof, a facsimile of such seal may be imprinted on the bonds if so authorized by the governing body of such unit, and it shall not be necessary in such case to impress such seal physically upon such bonds.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="215_43__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In case any officer whose signature or a facsimile of whose signature shall appear on any bonds or coupons shall cease to be such officer before the delivery of such bonds, such signature or such facsimile shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if he or she had remained in office until such delivery, and any bond may bear the facsimile signature of, or may be signed by, such persons as at the actual time of the execution of such bond shall be the proper officers to sign such bond although at the date of such bond such persons may not have been such officers.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
