<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.21/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.21/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/212.21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_212">
        <num>Chapter 212</num>
        <heading>Tax on Sales, Use, and Other Transactions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_212_21">
          <num>212.21</num>
          <heading>Declaration of legislative intent.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If any section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase or word of this chapter is for any reason held or declared to be unconstitutional, invalid, inoperative, ineffective, inapplicable, or void, such invalidity or unconstitutionality shall not be construed to affect the portions of this chapter not so held to be unconstitutional, void, invalid, or ineffective, or affect the application of this chapter to other circumstances not so held to be invalid, it being hereby declared to be the express legislative intent that any such unconstitutional, illegal, invalid, ineffective, inapplicable, or void portion or portions of this chapter did not induce its passage, and that without the inclusion of any such unconstitutional, illegal, invalid, ineffective, or void portions of this chapter, the Legislature would have enacted the valid and constitutional portions thereof.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="212_21__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase or word of this chapter is for any reason held or declared to be unconstitutional, invalid, inoperative, ineffective, inapplicable, or void, such invalidity or unconstitutionality shall not be construed to affect the portions of this chapter not so held to be unconstitutional, void, invalid, or ineffective, or affect the application of this chapter to other circumstances not so held to be invalid, it being hereby declared to be the express legislative intent that any such unconstitutional, illegal, invalid, ineffective, inapplicable, or void portion or portions of this chapter did not induce its passage, and that without the inclusion of any such unconstitutional, illegal, invalid, ineffective, or void portions of this chapter, the Legislature would have enacted the valid and constitutional portions thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_21__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is hereby declared to be the specific legislative intent to tax each and every sale, admission, use, storage, consumption, or rental levied and set forth in this chapter, except as to such sale, admission, use, storage, consumption, or rental as shall be specifically exempted therefrom by this chapter subject to the conditions appertaining to such exemption. It is further declared to be the specific legislative intent that should any exemption or attempted exemption from the tax or the operation or imposition of the tax or taxes be declared to be invalid, ineffective, inapplicable, unconstitutional, or void for any reason, such declaration shall not affect the tax or taxes imposed herein, but such sale, admission, use, storage, consumption, or rental, or any of them exempted or attempted to be exempted from the tax or taxes or the operation or the imposition of the tax or taxes, shall be subject to the tax or taxes and the operation and imposition thereof to the same extent as if such exemption or attempted exemption had never been included herein.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_21__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is further declared to be the specific legislative intent to exempt from the tax or taxes or from the operation or the imposition thereof only such sales, admissions, uses, storages, consumption, or rentals in relation to or in respect of the things set forth by this chapter as exempted from the tax to the extent that such exemptions are in accordance with the provisions of the constitutions of the state and of the United States. It is further declared to be the specific legislative intent to tax each and every taxable privilege made subject to the tax or taxes, except such sales, admissions, uses, storages, consumptions, or rentals as are specifically exempted therefrom by this chapter to the extent that such exemptions are in accordance with the provisions of the constitutions of the state and of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_21__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It being further declared to be the specific legislative intent that in the event any exemption or attempted exemption of any sale, admissions, use, storage, consumption, or rental from the tax or taxes imposed by this chapter is for any reason declared to be unconstitutional, ineffective, inapplicable, or void, that then and in such event each and every such sale, admission, use, storage, consumption, or rental shall be subject to the tax or taxes imposed by this chapter as fully and to the same extent as if such exemption or attempted exemption had never been included herein, it being declared to be the specific legislative intent that no unconstitutional, invalid, ineffective, inapplicable, or void exemption or attempted exemption or exemptions or attempted exemptions induced the passage of this chapter, it being further declared to be the specific legislative intent that without the inclusion herein of any such unconstitutional, invalid, ineffective, inapplicable, or void exemption or attempted exemption, exemptions or attempted exemptions, the valid portions of this chapter would have been enacted.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212_21__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is the legislative intent that the repeal of any provision heretofore exempting in whole or part any item or transaction from the tax imposed by this chapter shall result in the full imposition of the applicable tax to any such item or transaction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
