<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.21/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.21/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_202">
        <num>Chapter 202</num>
        <heading>Communications Services Tax Simplification Law</heading>
        <section eId="sec_202_21">
          <num>202.21</num>
          <heading>Effective dates; procedures for informing dealers of communications services of tax levies and rate changes.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any adoption, repeal, or change in the rate of a local communications services tax imposed under s.202.19is effective with respect to taxable services included on bills that are dated on or after the January 1 subsequent to such adoption, repeal, or change. A municipality or county adopting, repealing, or changing the rate of such tax must notify the department of the adoption, repeal, or change by September 1 immediately preceding such January 1. Notification must be furnished on a form prescribed by the department and must specify the rate of tax; the effective date of the adoption, repeal, or change thereof; and the name, mailing address, and telephone number of a person designated by the municipality or county to respond to inquiries concerning the tax. The department shall provide notice of such adoption, repeal, or change to all affected dealers of communications services at least 90 days before the effective date of the tax. Any local government that adjusts the rate of its local communications services tax by emergency ordinance or resolution pursuant to s.202.20(2) shall notify the department of the new tax rate immediately upon its adoption. The department shall provide written notice of the adoption of the new rate to all affected dealers within 30 days after receiving such notice. In any notice to providers or publication of local tax rates for purposes of this chapter, the department shall express the rate for a municipality or charter county as the sum of the tax rates levied within such jurisdiction pursuant to s.202.19(2)(a) and (5), and shall express the rate for any other county as the sum of the tax rates levied pursuant to s.202.19(2)(b) and (5). The department is not liable for any loss of or decrease in revenue by reason of any error, omission, or untimely action that results in the nonpayment of a tax imposed under s.202.19.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
