<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.155"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.155"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.155/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.155/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.155/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/202.155/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_202">
        <num>Chapter 202</num>
        <heading>Communications Services Tax Simplification Law</heading>
        <section eId="sec_202_155">
          <num>202.155</num>
          <heading>Special rules for mobile communications services.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A home service provider shall be responsible for obtaining and maintaining the customer’s place of primary use. Subject to subsections (2) and (3), if the home service provider’s reliance on information provided by its customer is in good faith:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="202_155__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A home service provider shall be responsible for obtaining and maintaining the customer’s place of primary use. Subject to subsections (2) and (3), if the home service provider’s reliance on information provided by its customer is in good faith:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="202_155__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The home service provider shall be entitled to rely on the applicable residential or business street address supplied by such customer.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="202_155__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The home service provider shall be held harmless from liability for any additional taxes imposed by or pursuant to this chapter or chapter 203 which are based on a different determination of such customer’s place of primary use.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="202_155__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in subsection (3), a home service provider shall be allowed to treat the address used for tax purposes for any customer under a service contract in effect on August 1, 2002, as that customer’s place of primary use for the remaining term of such service contract or agreement, excluding any extension or renewal of such service contract or agreement.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="202_155__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall provide notice to the customer of its intent to redetermine the customer’s place of primary use. If a final order is entered ruling that the address used by a home service provider as a customer’s place of primary use does not meet the definition of “place of primary use” provided by s.202.11, the department shall notify the home service provider of the proper address to be used as such customer’s place of primary use. The home service provider shall begin using the correct address within 120 days.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="202_155__subsec_3__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The department shall provide notice to the customer of its intent to redetermine the customer’s place of primary use. If a final order is entered ruling that the address used by a home service provider as a customer’s place of primary use does not meet the definition of “place of primary use” provided by s.202.11, the department shall notify the home service provider of the proper address to be used as such customer’s place of primary use. The home service provider shall begin using the correct address within 120 days.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="202_155__subsec_3__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The department shall provide notice to the home service provider of its intent to redetermine the assignment of a taxing jurisdiction by a home service provider under s.202.22. If a final order is entered ruling that the jurisdiction assigned by the home service provider is incorrect, the department shall notify the home service provider of the proper jurisdictional assignment. The home service provider shall begin using the correct jurisdictional assignment within 120 days.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="202_155__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a mobile communications service is not subject to the taxes administered pursuant to this chapter, and if the sales price of such service is aggregated with and not separately stated from the sales price of services subject to tax, then the nontaxable mobile communications service shall be treated as being subject to tax unless the home service provider can reasonably identify the sales price of the service not subject to tax from its books and records kept in the regular course of business.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="202_155__subsec_4__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a mobile communications service is not subject to the taxes administered pursuant to this chapter, and if the sales price of such service is aggregated with and not separately stated from the sales price of services subject to tax, then the nontaxable mobile communications service shall be treated as being subject to tax unless the home service provider can reasonably identify the sales price of the service not subject to tax from its books and records kept in the regular course of business.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="202_155__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a mobile communications service is not subject to the taxes administered pursuant to this chapter, a customer may not rely upon the nontaxability of such service unless the customer’s home service provider separately states the sales price of such nontaxable services or the home service provider elects, after receiving a written request from the customer in the form required by the provider, to provide verifiable data based upon the home service provider’s books and records that are kept in the regular course of business that reasonably identifies the sales price of such nontaxable service.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
