<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0153"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0153"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0153/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0153/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0153/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0153/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>Chapter 216</num>
        <heading>Planning and Budgeting</heading>
        <section eId="sec_216_0153">
          <num>216.0153</num>
          <heading>Comprehensive state-owned real property system.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whereas, the Legislature finds that it is in the best interest of the state to identify surplus property and dispose of such property owned by the state that is unnecessary to achieving the state’s responsibilities, that may cost more to maintain than the revenue generated, that does not serve any public purpose, or from which the state may derive a substantially similar public purpose under private ownership.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="216_0153__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Environmental Protection shall create, administer, and maintain a comprehensive system for all state lands and real property leased, owned, rented, and otherwise occupied or maintained by any state agency, by the judicial branch, and by any water management district. The comprehensive state-owned real property system shall allow the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund to perform its statutory responsibilities and the Division of State Lands in the Department of Environmental Protection to conduct strategic analyses and prepare annual valuation and disposition analyses and recommendations for all state real property assets.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The comprehensive state-owned real property system must contain a database that includes an accurate inventory of all real property that is leased, owned, rented, occupied, or managed by the state, the judicial branch, or the water management districts.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Division of State Lands in the Department of Environmental Protection shall be the statewide custodian of the real property information and shall be accountable for its accuracy.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All state agencies and water management districts shall enter required real property information in the comprehensive system according to standards published by the Division of State Lands.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_0153__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The comprehensive state-owned real property system must accomplish the following objectives:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Eliminate the need for redundant state real property information collection processes and state agency information systems.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Reduce the need to lease or acquire additional real property as a result of an annual surplus valuation, utilization, and disposition analysis.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_2__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Enable regional planning as a tool for cost-effective buy, sell, and lease decisions.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_2__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Increase state revenues and maximize operational efficiencies by annually identifying those state-owned real properties that are the best candidates for surplus or disposition.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_2__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ensure all state real property is identified by collaborating and integrating with the Department of Revenue data as submitted by the county property appraisers.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0153__subsec_2__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Implement required functionality and processes for state agencies to electronically submit all applicable real property information using a web browser application.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_0153__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>By October 1, 2010, and annually thereafter, the Division of State Lands in the Department of Environmental Protection shall submit to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a report that lists the state-owned real property recommended for disposition, including a report by the Department of Management Services of surplus buildings recommended for disposition. The report shall include specific information that documents the valuation and analysis process used to identify the specific state-owned real property recommended for disposition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
