<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0236"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0236"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0236/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0236/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0236/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.0236/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>Chapter 216</num>
        <heading>Planning and Budgeting</heading>
        <section eId="sec_216_0236">
          <num>216.0236</num>
          <heading>Agency fees for regulatory services or oversight; criteria.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It is the intent of the Legislature that all costs of providing a regulatory service or regulating a profession or business be borne solely by those who receive the service or who are subject to regulation. It is also the intent of the Legislature that the fees charged for providing a regulatory service or regulating a profession or business be reasonable and take into account the differences between the types of professions or businesses being regulated. Moreover, it is the intent of the Legislature that state agencies operate as efficiently as possible and regularly report to the Legislature additional methods by which to streamline their operational costs.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="216_0236__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is the intent of the Legislature that all costs of providing a regulatory service or regulating a profession or business be borne solely by those who receive the service or who are subject to regulation. It is also the intent of the Legislature that the fees charged for providing a regulatory service or regulating a profession or business be reasonable and take into account the differences between the types of professions or businesses being regulated. Moreover, it is the intent of the Legislature that state agencies operate as efficiently as possible and regularly report to the Legislature additional methods by which to streamline their operational costs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_0236__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In accordance with the instructions for legislative budget requests, each state agency shall examine the fees it charges for providing regulatory services and oversight to businesses or professions. The annual examination shall determine whether operational efficiencies can be achieved in the underlying program, whether the regulatory activity is an appropriate function that the agency should continue at its current level, and whether the fees charged for each regulatory program are:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="216_0236__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Based on revenue projections that are prepared using generally accepted governmental accounting procedures or official estimates by the Revenue Estimating Conference, if applicable;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0236__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Adequate to cover both the direct and indirect costs of providing the regulatory service or oversight; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_0236__subsec_2__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Reasonable and take into account differences between the types of professions or businesses that are regulated.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_0236__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the agency determines that the fees charged for regulatory services or oversight to businesses or professions are not adequate to cover program costs and that an appropriation from other state funds is necessary to supplement the direct or indirect costs of providing a regulatory service or regulating a program, the agency shall present to the Governor and the Legislature as part of its legislative budget request information regarding alternatives for realigning revenues or costs to make the regulatory service or program totally self-sufficient or shall demonstrate that the service or program provides substantial benefits to the public which justify a partial subsidy from other state funds. The Legislature shall review the alternatives during the next regular session.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_0236__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Legislature shall review the regulatory fee structure for all businesses and professions at least once every 5 years. The schedule for such review may be included in the legislative budget instructions developed pursuant to the requirements of s.216.023.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
