<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.151"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.151"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.151/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.151/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.151/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.151/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>Chapter 216</num>
        <heading>Planning and Budgeting</heading>
        <section eId="sec_216_151">
          <num>216.151</num>
          <heading>Duties of the Executive Office of the Governor.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of the Executive Office of the Governor to:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Make a detailed study, as necessary, of each of the several state agencies, with a view toward ascertaining and determining the needs thereof; whether changes should be made in existing organizations, their activities and methods of operation; what appropriation should be made therefor; whether the operations and activities of different agencies or within the same agencies should be combined, consolidated, or integrated or should be regrouped and rearranged, all to the end of securing greater economy without sacrificing efficiency in the operations of such agencies. In order to accomplish this type of study, the Executive Office of the Governor may request any or all agencies to submit a budget plan with respect to targets established by the Governor. Such a request shall not influence the agencies’ independent judgments in making legislative budget requests, as required by law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prepare an analysis of the legislative budget requests submitted by state agencies and the judicial branch covering their respective operational and fixed capital outlay requirements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prepare such other data as will reflect the financial condition of the state and its agencies at the close of the prior fiscal year and an estimate of what that condition will be at the close of the current fiscal year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prepare a statement of policy to assure that fixed capital outlay appropriations recommended by the Governor will be consistent with recommended operational standards related to programs and utilization.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide to the Legislature any information used to justify and evaluate the Governor’s recommended balanced budget.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Consult with the Office of State-Federal Relations in Washington, D.C., under the Executive Office of the Governor, in order to:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="216_151__subsec_6__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evaluate current levels of federal authorization to determine how the state might obtain a more equitable share of federal funding.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_151__subsec_6__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Develop a federal-aid formula database in order to catalog all existing federal formulas and identify funding inequities.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_151__subsec_6__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Establish a federal formula modeling capability, to the extent allowable by resources. Such a modeling component should be designed in a manner which assists the state and its federal representatives in assessing periodic legislation before Congress which disseminates financial assistance to state and local governments based on a formula or set of formulas.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_151__subsec_6__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Develop and implement a communications network to link the Legislature and the executive branch with Florida’s Congressional Delegation. Such a network should allow for the rapid transmittal of:</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_151__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Perform such other duties as may be required by law or by the Governor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
