<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.231"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.231"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.231/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.231/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.231/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/216.231/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>Chapter 216</num>
        <heading>Planning and Budgeting</heading>
        <section eId="sec_216_231">
          <num>216.231</num>
          <heading>Release of certain classified appropriations.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any appropriation to the Executive Office of the Governor which is classified as an emergency, as defined in s.252.34, may be released only with the approval of the Governor. The state agency, or the judicial branch, desiring the use of the emergency appropriation shall submit to the Executive Office of the Governor application in writing setting forth the facts from which the alleged need arises. The Executive Office of the Governor shall, at a public hearing, review such application promptly and approve or disapprove the applications as the circumstances may warrant. All actions of the Executive Office of the Governor shall be reported to the legislative appropriations committees, and the committees may advise the Executive Office of the Governor relative to the release of such funds.</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="216_231__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any appropriation to the Executive Office of the Governor which is classified as an emergency, as defined in s.252.34, may be released only with the approval of the Governor. The state agency, or the judicial branch, desiring the use of the emergency appropriation shall submit to the Executive Office of the Governor application in writing setting forth the facts from which the alleged need arises. The Executive Office of the Governor shall, at a public hearing, review such application promptly and approve or disapprove the applications as the circumstances may warrant. All actions of the Executive Office of the Governor shall be reported to the legislative appropriations committees, and the committees may advise the Executive Office of the Governor relative to the release of such funds.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="216_231__subsec_1__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any appropriation to the Executive Office of the Governor which is classified as an emergency, as defined in s.252.34, may be released only with the approval of the Governor. The state agency, or the judicial branch, desiring the use of the emergency appropriation shall submit to the Executive Office of the Governor application in writing setting forth the facts from which the alleged need arises. The Executive Office of the Governor shall, at a public hearing, review such application promptly and approve or disapprove the applications as the circumstances may warrant. All actions of the Executive Office of the Governor shall be reported to the legislative appropriations committees, and the committees may advise the Executive Office of the Governor relative to the release of such funds.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="216_231__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The release of appropriated funds classified as “emergency” shall be approved only if an act or circumstance caused by an act of God, civil disturbance, natural disaster, or other circumstance of an emergency nature threatens, endangers, or damages the property, safety, health, or welfare of the state or its residents, which condition has not been provided for in appropriation acts of the Legislature. Funds allocated for this purpose may be used to pay overtime pay to personnel of agencies called upon to perform extra duty because of any civil disturbance or other emergency as defined in s.252.34and to provide the required state match for federal grants under the federal Disaster Relief Act.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_231__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The release of appropriated funds classified as “deficiency” shall be approved only when a General Revenue Fund appropriation for operations of a state agency or of the judicial branch is inadequate because the workload or cost of the operation exceeds that anticipated by the Legislature and a determination has been made by the Governor that the deficiency will result in an impairment of the activities of an agency or of the judicial branch to the extent that the agency is unable to carry out its program as provided by the Legislature in the general appropriations acts. These funds may not be used for creation of any new agency or program, for increases of salary, or for the construction or equipping of additional buildings.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="216_231__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, moneys appropriated in any appropriations act to the Governor for discretionary contingencies may be expended at his or her discretion to promote general government and intergovernmental cooperation and to enhance the image of the state. All funds expended for such purposes shall be accounted for, and a report showing the amounts expended, the names of the persons receiving the amounts expended, and the purpose of each expenditure shall be annually reported to the Auditor General and the legislative appropriations committees.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
