<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#fl-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/196.26"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/196.26"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-fl"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/196.26/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/196.26/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#fl-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-fl/act/fsa/196.26/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-fl/act/fsa/196.26/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="fl-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-fl/legislature" showAs="Florida Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_196">
        <num>Chapter 196</num>
        <heading>Exemption</heading>
        <section eId="sec_196_26">
          <num>196.26</num>
          <heading>Exemption for real property dedicated in perpetuity for conservation purposes.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this section:</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Allowed commercial uses” means commercial uses that are allowed by the conservation easement encumbering the land exempt from taxation under this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Conservation easement” means the property right described in s.704.06.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Conservation purposes” means:</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_1__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Dedicated in perpetuity” means that the land is encumbered by an irrevocable, perpetual conservation easement.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Land that is dedicated in perpetuity for conservation purposes and that is used exclusively for conservation purposes is exempt from ad valorem taxation. Such exclusive use does not preclude the receipt of income from activities that are consistent with a management plan when the income is used to implement, maintain, and manage the management plan.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Land that is dedicated in perpetuity for conservation purposes and that is used for allowed commercial uses is exempt from ad valorem taxation to the extent of 50 percent of the assessed value of the land.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Land that comprises less than 40 contiguous acres does not qualify for the exemption provided in this section unless, in addition to meeting the other requirements of this section, the use of the land for conservation purposes is determined by the Acquisition and Restoration Council created in s.259.035to fulfill a clearly delineated state conservation policy and yield a significant public benefit. In making its determination of public benefit, the Acquisition and Restoration Council must give particular consideration to land that:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Contains a natural sinkhole or natural spring that serves a water recharge or production function;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Contains a unique geological feature;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provides habitat for endangered or threatened species;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provides nursery habitat for marine and estuarine species;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provides protection or restoration of vulnerable coastal areas;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Preserves natural shoreline habitat; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="196_26__subsec_4__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provides retention of natural open space in otherwise densely built-up areas.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The conservation easement that serves as the basis for the exemption granted by this section must include baseline documentation as to the natural values to be protected on the land and may include a management plan that details the management of the land so as to effectuate the conservation of natural resources on the land.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Buildings, structures, and other improvements situated on land receiving the exemption provided in this section and the land area immediately surrounding the buildings, structures, and improvements must be assessed separately pursuant to chapter 193. However, structures and other improvements that are auxiliary to the use of the land for conservation purposes are exempt to the same extent as the underlying land.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Land that qualifies for the exemption provided in this section the allowed commercial uses of which include agriculture must comply with the most recent best management practices if adopted by rule of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As provided in s.704.06(8) and (9), water management districts with jurisdiction over lands receiving the exemption provided in this section have a third-party right of enforcement to enforce the terms of the applicable conservation easement for any easement that is not enforceable by a federal or state agency, county, municipality, or water management district when the holder of the easement is unable or unwilling to enforce the terms of the easement.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="196_26__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Acquisition and Restoration Council, created in s.259.035, shall maintain a list of nonprofit entities that are qualified to enforce the provisions of a conservation easement.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
